A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Linda Nochlin papers
circa 1876
1937-2017
Archives of American Art
Nochlin, Linda
AAA.nochlind
Archival Resource Key
31.2 Linear feet
3.62 Gigabytes
The papers of feminist art historian and educator Linda Nochlin measure 31.2 linear feet and 3.62 gigabytes and date from circa 1876, 1937 to 2017. The collection is comprised of biographical materials; date books and notebooks; correspondence; writing project files that include material on Gustave Courbet and realism, bathers and the body, essays and lectures on 19th century art among other topics, artists, and smaller writing projects; professional files containing material on conferences and fellowships; teaching files detailing courses taught by Nochlin at New York University Institute of Fine Arts and other institutions; printed materials; artwork; and photographic materials that document Nochlin and her relationships with family, colleagues and friends, and artists.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated in 2018 by Daisy Pommer, Linda Nochlin's daughter.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Researchers interested in accessing born-digital records or audiovisual recordings in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
Biographical / Historical
Linda Nochlin (1931-2017) was a feminist art historian and professor at New York University Institute of Fine Arts in New York, New York. She is widely known for her essay first published in 1971, "Why Have There Been No Great Women Artists?," that explored the institutional systems in place for analyzing art history and their impacts on women artists. In 1976, Nochlin co-curated Women Artists: 1550-1950 alongside Ann Sutherland Harris at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art, and in 2007 she co-curated with Maura Reilly the Global Feminisms Exhibition at the Brooklyn Museum. Both exhibitions are considered landmark exhibitions of women artists.
Nochlin was born in Brooklyn, New York. She attended the Brooklyn Ethical Culture School and Midwood High School before enrolling in Vassar College where she majored in philosophy with minors in Greek and art history. After graduating in 1951, she went on to earn a master's degree in English from Columbia University in 1952. In 1963, she earned her PhD in art history from the Institute of Fine Arts. Nochlin's PhD dissertation, "Gustave Courbet: A Study of Style and Society," marked the beginning of her lifelong study of the 19th-Century French artist Gustave Courbet.
Nochlin taught at Yale University, the Graduate Center at the City University of New York, and Vassar College. She was also a visiting professor at Columbia University, Hunter College, Stanford University, Williams College, and Yale University, and later became the Lila Acheson Wallace Professor Emerita of Modern Art at the Institute of Fine Arts.
Nochlin authored numerous art history books including Realism (1971), The Politics of Vision: Essays on Nineteenth-Century Art and Society (1989), Representing Women (1999), The Body in Pieces: The Fragment as a Metaphor of Modernity (1994), Bathers, Bodies, Beauty: The Visceral Eye (2006), Courbet (2007), and Misère: The Visual Representation of Misery in the 19th Century (2018).
Scope and Contents
The papers of feminist art historian and educator Linda Nochlin measure 31.2 linear feet and 3.62 gigabytes and date from circa 1876, 1937 to 2017. The collection is comprised of biographical materials; date books and notebooks; correspondence; writing project files that include material on Gustave Courbet and realism, bathers and the body, essays and lectures on 19th century art among other topics, artists, and smaller writing projects; professional files containing material on conferences and fellowships; teaching files detailing courses taught by Nochlin at New York University Institute of Fine Arts and other institutions; printed materials; artwork; and photographic materials that document Nochlin and her relationships with family, colleagues and friends, and artists.
Biographical materials include two address books; awards and prizes; certificates and diplomas; childhood writings and notes, assignments, and school newsletters; course work at Vassar College and NYU's Institute of Fine Arts; honors; and one sound recording and three transcripts of Nochlin interviews with Alain Veinstein, Dan Karlholm, Jon Weiner, and Moira Roth.
Over 150 date books and notebooks spanning nearly 60 years contain appointments, reminders, travel plans, thoughts on art, journal entries, daily activities, to-do lists, contact information, fiction writing, and other small notations. Correspondence is with family; close colleagues and artists Ewa Lajer-Burcharth, Zuka Mitelberg, Joan Mitchell, and Philip Pearlstein; and professional contacts regarding speaking engagements, publishing projects, exhibitions, artists' work, conferences, and events.
The bulk of the collection documents Nochlin's prolific writing career that includes her lifelong research and work on Gustave Courbet, realism, bathers and the body, as well as numerous essays and lectures, research and writings on artists, and various other writing projects.
Files for professional activities contain material for conferences and symposiums that include 11 sound and video recordings, grants, fellowships, and travel arrangements and expenses. Teaching files consist of documentation for courses taught by Nochlin at New York University Institute of Fine Arts, Vassar College, Yale University, and other academic institutions.
Publications and other printed materials include annotated books, booklets, clippings, exhibition catalogs, journals and magazines, newsletters, offprints, five video recordings of broadcasts and documentary material, flyers, invitations, posters, and postcards. Artwork includes sketches in ink, charcoal, paint, and pencil created during Nochlin's childhood into her early 20s, along with artwork by children, and one video art recording by Zoulikha Bouabdellah.
Photographs and negatives are of Nochlin with artists Nancy Graves, Sebastian Horsley, and Shirley Jaffe; childhood classmates; friends and colleagues; students; and travels to Europe. Also included are photographs of works of art, personal photographs of family members, and portraits and snapshots of Nochlin.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as nine series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, circa 1940-2012 (1.0 linear feet; Box 1, OV 35 / 0.003 GB; ER01-ER03)
Series 2: Datebooks and Notebooks, 1959-2017 (2.5 linear feet; Boxes 2-5, OV 35 / 0.001 GB; ER004)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1946-2014 (2.0 linear feet; Boxes 5-7, OV 35 / 0.058GB; ER005-ER011; ER120)
Series 4: Writing Project Files, circa 1876, 1953-2016 (17.0 linear feet; Boxes 7-21, 30-31, 33-34, OVs 36-37 / 3.72 GB; ER012-ER102)
Series 5: Professional Files, 1957-2012 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 22-23 / 0.001 GB; ER103)
Series 6: Teaching Files, 1953-2012 (2.5 linear feet; Boxes 23-25, OV 36 / 0.016 GB; ER104-ER119)
Series 7: Printed Materials, 1939-2017 (3.0 linear feet; Boxes 26-28, 32, 34, OVs 39-40)
Series 8: Artwork, circa 1940-2004 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 28, 34, OV 38)
Series 9: Photographic Materials, circa 1935-circa 2010 (1.0 linear feet; Boxes 28-29, 34)
Existence and Location of Copies
All of the audiovisual recordings in the collection were digitized for research access in 2019 and are available at Archives of American Art offices.
Related Materials
Also found at the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview of Linda Nochlin conducted on June 9-30, 2010 by James McElhinney, for the Archives of American Art's Oral History of Women in the Visual Arts project at Nochlin's home in New York, N.Y.
Art historians -- New York (State) -- New York; Feminists; Interviews; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Women art historians; Realism; Women artists; Diaries; Educators -- New York (State) -- New York; Mitchell, Joan, 1926-1992; Pearlstein, Philip, 1924-; Zuka; Courbet, Gustave, 1819-1877; Lajer-Burcharth, Ewa
- Biographical Materials, circa 1940-2012; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 1, OV 35; 0.003 Gigabytes ER01-ER03
  Scope and Contents
  Nochlin's biographical materials include two address books, awards and prizes, certificates from the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and her elementary school, and digital curriculum vitae; digital biographies and poetry, childhood writings, class notes, assignments, and newsletters demonstrating Nochlin's early writing and drawing abilities; undergraduate and graduate class notes and papers related to art, philosophy, and politics along with other records collected while attending Vassar College and NYU's Institute of Fine Arts; diplomas and degrees; material from events honoring Nochlin; and one sound recording and three transcripts of Nochlin interviews with Alain Veinstein, Dan Karlholm, Jon Weiner, and Moira Roth.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by format or subject, then arranged chronologically within the folders.
  - Address Books, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
    2 books
  - Awards and Prizes, 1945-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - Certificate, Ethical Culture Camp Summer Course, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Childhood Writings, Camp Wildwood Magazine, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Childhood Writings, Poetry, 1946-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Class Assignments, English Compositions, 1940-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Class Assignments, English Project, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Class Assignments, Essay on China, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Class Assignments, Miscellaneous Assignments, circa 1940-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Class Notes, Art History, 1949-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Class Notes, English Class, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class Notes, Late Antique Art, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class Notes, Late Antique Art, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Columbia University, Master of Arts Degree and Report Card, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1992-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 13 computer files (Folder ER001)
  - Degree, Courtauld Institute of Art Honorary Degree, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Diplomas, Elementary and High School, 1943; 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduation Program, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Honors, Appraisers Association of America Honoring Nochlin Programs, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Honors, ArtTable Award for Distinguished Service to the Visual Arts Program, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Honors, Symposiums in Honor of Nochlin Program Schedules, 1999; 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Identification Cards, 1967-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, David to Delacroix Class Notes, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, Paper on 19th Century Painting, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, Written Questions for Oral Exam, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Interview Broadcast, Nochlin Interviewed by Alain Veinstein on French Culture Radio, 1994; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Interview Transcript Draft, Nochlin Interviewed by Dan Karlholm for The Art Bulletin, 2011-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Interview Transcript Final Draft, Nochlin Interviewed by Jon Weiner - "Paris Commune Photos at a New York Gallery", 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Interview Transcript Draft, Nochlin Interviewed by Moira Roth - "Of Self and History: Exchanges with Linda Nochlin" for Art Journal, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Memorial Program for Richard Pommer, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Name Change, Documents for Proof, circa 1954; 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Poetry, 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER003)
  - School Newsletters, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - School Newsletters, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - School Newsletters, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - School Newsletters, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - School Progress Reports, 1941-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - School Report Card, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - School Souvenir Journals, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook/Sketchbook, "Good News" (1 of 2), 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook/Sketchbook, "Good News" (2 of 2), 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Short Bios, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER002)
  - Vassar College, Commencement and Fellowship, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Vassar College, Documents Regarding Travel to England, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Vassar College, Documents Regarding Travel to England, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - Vassar College, Essays, 1949-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Vassar College, Exam Essay Book, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Vassar College, Paper on Beatrice Webb and Soviet Communism, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Vassar College, Paper on Delacroix and Romanticism, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Vassar College, Paper on Philosophy, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Vassar College, Reunion Yearbook, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Vassar College, Walter Friedlaender Bibliography, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Vassar College, Yearbook, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Datebooks and Notebooks, 1959-2017; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 2-5, OV 35; 0.001 Gigabytes ER004
  The series contains 53 date books, 98 notebooks, and digital journaling exercises spanning from 1959 to 2017.
  The date books contain Nochlin's appointments and reminders pertaining to speaking engagements, travel plans, and other professional, as well as personal plans. The notebooks are intermittently dated by hand and contain similar content as the date books. Additionally, they are interspersed with Nochlin's thoughts on art, journal entries, daily activities, to-do lists, contact information, exercise and food logs, and some fiction writing.
  The series is arranged by format with date books at the beginning, followed by notebooks. Formats are arranged chronologically.
  - Datebook, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Datebook, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    3 books
  - Datebook, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Datebook, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Datebook, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Datebook, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Datebook, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Datebook, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Datebook, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    5 books
  - Datebook, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    4 books
  - Datebook, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Datebook, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Datebook, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Datebook, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Datebook, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Datebook, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Datebook, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Datebook, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Datebook, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Datebook, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - Datebook, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Datebook, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Datebook (1 of 2), 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    1 book
  - Datebook (2 of 2), 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Datebook (1 of 2), 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Datebook (2 of 2), 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Datebook, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Datebook, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Datebook, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Datebook, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Datebook, 2016-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, January 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, April 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, September 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, December 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, 2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Twenty Line Journaling Exercises, 1997; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER004)
- Correspondence, 1946-2014; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-7, OV 35; 0.058 Gigabytes ER005-ER011, ER120
  Most of the Nochlin's correspondence is professional in nature discussing speaking engagements, publishing projects, exhibitions, artists' work, conferences, and other professional events. Nochlin's earliest correspondence in the collection is with her family discussing her life at Vassar College and her student trip abroad to the United Kingdom. More personal correspondence is with close colleagues and artists Ewa Lajer-Burcharth, Zuka Mitelberg, Joan Mitchell, and Philip Pearlstein. Folders may contain manuscripts which were often sent to Nochlin for her professional opinion or as possible research for her own projects, printed material, and other records related to the correspondence.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by last name or subject. Correspondence in which only first names are known are files under "First." Correspondence in which the name is unidentified or illegible is filed under "Unidentified or Illegible." The contents of each folder are in chronological order beginning with undated material.
  - A, circa 1983-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Incorporated, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Aptekar, Ken, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Art Bulletin, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Association of Historians of Nineteenth-Century Art, circa 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - B, 1988-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Bibliothèque Nationale Regarding "Bad Mother", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER005)
  - Buszek, Maria Elena, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - C, 1969-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Cohen, Sorel, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - D, 1986-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Dahesh Museum, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Dahesh Museum, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - Dardanello, Pino, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Diederen, Roger, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Droll, Donald, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - E, 1986-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Emails, circa 2005-2016; Archival Resource Key; 0.011 Gigabytes 120 emails in 110 computer files (Folder ER006)
    Emails cover numerous topics and projects, and were organized into groupings by the donor and exported upon accession. Access files to be served in the delivery module of ePADD.
  - Email Related Files, Digital Documents, Archival Resource Key; 0.045 Gigabytes 206 computer files (Folder ER120)
    Files cover a number of topics and often represent various document drafts. They were labeled as related to email but the exact relationship is not well documented.
  - Emily Mary Osborn's Nameless and Friendless Copyright, Regarding, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ettinger, Tom, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - F, 1989-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Family, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)